

REDA HAQ

Front End Developer

redahaq.dev

<u>@redahaq</u>
<u>github.com/redahaq</u>
redahaq@gmail.com

ABOUT

I am a curious, creative developer. I have experience crafting digital communications campaigns with people at their heart.

I love all things code, UX and UI. I care deeply about quality, love a challenge, and am dedicated to continuous learning. I also like to encourage a sense of camaraderie when working in a team.

I hope to create experiences with accessibility and performance in mind, using Design Thinking and Agile methodologies.

I enjoy keeping up with the latest in the industry by **attending meetups** such as Front End Monthly and React JS Girls. I'm also grateful to be paying it forward by **mentoring** at Codebar and FAC meetups.

TECH STACK/TOOLING

Javascript Tape

HTML5 NYC & IstanbulCSS3 CodeCov

React Travis Cl
Git & Github lest

Git & Github Jest
Express React Testing Library

Handlebars Cypress
REST APIs Heroku

Figma Netlify
Photoshop NodeJS
VS Code PostGreSQL

Agile Methodologies, Design Thinking, Kanban, Scrum, TDD, Debugging

EXPERIENCE

Tablet game to teach 3-6 yr-olds about recycling. A drag and drop Progressive Web App designed in Figma, bootstrapped with Create React App and tested with Jest and React Testing Library. Brought to life with keyframe-animated SVGs.

- Refactored DOM-manipulation into React Hooks, and simplified code using abstraction
- Used **promises** and **async/await** to manage async flow
- Optimised SVGs to improve performance, loved learning about and using Styled Components

SafeSpace: Musician's Union Feb 2020 Client Project: 1wk design sprint, 2 wk-long build sprints

A site for the Musician's Union to enable reporting of sexual harassment at work. Create React App styled with customised React Material Web Components on the front and integrated with an Airtable database using Netlify Lambda Functions on the back. We built our own forms!

- As UX/UI lead, I was invested in ensuring a sensitive approach to the user journey, design and copy
- Achieved learning goals of using Material UI, and applying Cypress to conduct end-to-end tests
- Used React Router **URL params** to render dynamic routes

Full Stack Developer

Founders and Coders | Oct 2019 - March 2020

18-week bootcamp through which I've become proficient in the fundamentals of JavaScript before frameworks

- Discovered the importance of accessibility and how TDD, good documentation and code review can lead to highly readable, maintainable code
- Working collaboratively, presenting and discussing code have been invaluable parts of my experience



redahaq.dev

DIGITAL COMMS + MARKETING SKILLS

With an understanding of social psychology and what drives users online, I bring a holistic approach to my work as a developer.

- Integrated digital marketing
- Earned, Owned, Paid, Shared
- Competitor audits & insights
- Social Network Analysis
- Social Content Strategy
- Influencer Campaigns
- Loyalty/ CRM programmes
- SEO and SEM
- Google Analytics
- UX-driven campaigns
- Creative/ Copywriting
- Developing KPI frameworks
- Measurement and Analytics
- Evaluation and Reporting
- Reactive Marketing
- Crisis/ Issues Management
- Digital Trends

EDUCATION

2:1 BA English Literature and Creative Writing

2005 - 2008

Royal Holloway, University of London

A-Levels

Orpington

English Literature, Maths, Geography, Physics 2003 - 2005 Newstead Wood School,

PREVIOUS CAREER EXPERIENCE

Freelance Graphic Designer

Sid Valley Help | Feb 2018 - Jan 2019

- Designed fundraising poster for charity race night
- Designed tri-fold leaflet about the organisation, following brand guidelines and ensuring legibility for an aging population

Digital Comms and Marketing Manager

Business in the Community | March 2016 - Nov 2016

Drove digital marketing for the charity including strategy, social media, email marketing. Managed digital marketing of flagship events, Responsible Business Week and BITC Awards.

- Developed strategy and worked in cross-functional teams to deliver projects to time, scope and budget
- Liaised with in-house designer to create assets for digital marketing
- Used Google analytics data to increase conversions
- Conducted A/B testing to ensure optimisation of social media ads and set up Google Grants ads

Digital Strategist

Cohn and Wolfe (BCW Global) | July 2011 - July 2014

Created integrated, impactful programmes for global and national clients including Samsung, Nokia-MSFT, Dell, John Lewis, Lloyds, Ferrero, Merck, Universal.

- Everything from content strategy and leveraging paid and shared opportunities, to crisis communications
- Built strong relationships with clients, internal, external stakeholders and third party suppliers
- Hired and managed two excellent people, facilitating training and development
- London lead of the global Digital Innovation Group
- Won the company's Entrepreneur Award

INTERESTS

- Baking my next challenge is taking on croissants
- Yoga
- Interior design
- Salsa dancing